Her music. Her life. Her legacy.
Back to Black is a music, history, drama film directed by Sam Taylor-Johnson.
The extraordinary story of Amy Winehouse’s early rise to fame from her early days in Camden through the
making of her groundbreaking album, Back to Black that catapulted Winehouse to global fame.
Told through Amy’s eyes and inspired by her deeply personal lyrics, the film explores and embraces the many layers of the
iconic artist and the tumultuous love story at the center of one of the most legendary albums of all time.
Amy, played by Marisa Abela.
Blake, played by Jack O'Connell.
Mitch, played by Eddie Marsan.
Cynthia, played by Lesley Manville.
Janis, played by Juliet Cowan.
Nick Shymansky, played by Sam Buchanan.
Back to Black is a 2024 biographical drama film based on the life of
English singer-songwriter Amy Winehouse, played by Marisa Abela.
Directed by Sam Taylor-Johnson and written by Matt Greenhalgh, the film
also stars Jack O'Connell, Eddie Marsan and Lesley Manville.
Following the death of Winehouse in July 2011, several filmmakers
attempted to create biopic projects, but none of them progressed.
In 2018, Winehouse's estate announced they had signed a
deal for a film about her life and career.
By July 2022, StudioCanal moved forward with production, and
filming took place in London from January to April 2023.
The film was released theatrically by StudioCanal in Australia on 11 April
2024, and was released in the United Kingdom on 12 April 2024.
Focus Features released the film in the United States on 17 May 2024.
It has received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $51 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of biography, addiction, based on
true story, alcoholism, mental illness.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.